No!
My name is Kudo Shinichi.
I was a famous high school
student detective.
But one day, I went with my childhood
friend Ran to an amusement park and ...
...I witnessed a scene of some men in
black involved in some suspicious deal.
And then they made me take
a poison known as Apoptoxin 4869.
When I woke up...
..my body had been shrunken.
If they knew that Kudo Shinichi was still alive...
...the Black Organization could
bring harm to all those around me.
Naming myself Edogawa Conan...
...I solved cases while looking
for information on those men.
But this is a case that occurred 100
days before I became Edogawa Conan.
While taking a trip with Ran and others,
we came across the village's legend...
..and became involved in an
impossible murder case.
A series of mysteries occurred...
...and I, too, suffered
an unexpected trick.
Wait.
A rumor about the high school student
who's a great detective has appeared.
You've solved a murder case
once again, haven't you?
This time, it was a closed room case,
how did you figure out the murderer?
You were brilliant this time too, weren't you?
How did you feel when
the police detectives...
...found themselves in over
their heads as you solved it?
Ah, let's see...
Yes, this is me.
The high school student
detective, Kudo Shinichi.
Of course at the time I couldn't have
imagined that, in the near future...
...I would be reverting back to being
an elementary school student.
Well, how do I put it...
- Kudo.
- One word, please.
Oi!
Ha!
That was dangerous!
She's Mori Ran.
My childhood friend.
Deep down a good girl, but she's also
strong willed and gifted in karate.
We aren't dating though.
Anyway, let’s run, let’s run!
Itadakimasu!
Please don't hold back and
eat as much as you like.
Ran has been so worried about her
figure, that she hasn't been eating at all.
I am discouraged, you know.
Mom, that's not true.
Thank you very much.
I'll eat heartily.
Yeah, go ahead.
Well? Any good?
"It's bad!"
Lately...I've also been
worried about my figure.
It itches. Ah!
Mom, what's the matter?
Recently, when someone lies,
my left eye starts to itch.
Eh?
Well, I run into so many
incidents of it as a lawyer...
...but it troubles me most
when my clients start lying.
Because of that, my eye's
gotten very sensitive to lies.
It's my predisposition
towards cause and effect.
Ah, it's kind of an occupational disease.
This person is Kisaki Eri.
She's a shrewd lawyer who never
loses a case and she's Ran's mother.
However she and Ran's father,
Mori Kogoro, live separately...
...and are negotiating their divorce.
And? Shinichi, what
was that lie just now?
Eh? "Bad cook"
Ah, Mom, a visitor.
Eh? Who could that be?
Sonoko!
Ran, I'm here.
Hello, Kudo. Popular
as ever, aren't you?
I saw you on TV.
This stuff's awful! I don't want this.
I'm not happy about it.
I can't go home.
Then I'm just in time.
Say, it's very sudden., but how about
we all go to Jyugoya Village?
This is Suzuki Sonoko.
The daughter of the Suzuki Conglomerate.
She's one of Japan's richest people, but
she's sociable and follows the latest trends.
She's always inviting us to wherever
various incidents have occurred.
Jyugoya Village?
Papa's acquaintance built a villa there
and he's invited me to come visit.
Could it be this acquaintance
of your father's is...
Bingo!
Japan's biggest chain of izakayas
that you're the legal adviser for...
Wakura Group’s President Wakura!
Uncle Wakura said he really
wants you to come.
If Wakura is asking...can't
turn him down, now can I?
Yay!
Ah!
Huh?
What about Dad?
I don't want that person going with us.
Rascal!
Ras...
Like I said, it's "Pascal."
That's so ambiguous...
Normally a raccoon's name is Rascal.
Mine is far more clever
than any 'Rascal' would be.
Oh?
Oh, I just heard something.
It might be Pascal!
Please go take a look.
Eh?
You... want me to go up there?
Eh? You won't go up?
"Acrophobia"
Then I won't pay you.
I came because you said
there was a kidnapping.
Why is this happening to me...
Ah, did you say something just now?
No, no, no.
Oh! There, Wait...
By the way, this uncle is
Ran's father, Mori Kogoro.
He left the police and
opened a detective agency...
...but as for his ability...
..well, how can I put this...
Pascal.
Anyhow, we decided to leave him
behind and head to Jyugoya Village.
Pascal!
"Northeast Bus Stop Jyugoya Village"
We’re here at last....
But why are you still in
your school uniform?
No choice. I couldn't go home, after all.
Uncle Wakura, it's been awhile!
Yes... Welcome.
"Wakura Group President Wakura Isami"
Hello.
-It's been awhile.
-Yes it is.
Who is this?
Ah, my daughter.
My close friend, Mori Ran...
...and the famous high school student
detective, Kudo Shinichi
Hello.
A detective?
Wakura, we're sorry for forcing
ourselves upon you like this today.
Not at all, not at all.
It's an honor to have you come.
Welcome to the village
of the legendary Otori.
"Village of the legendary Otori"?
In this village a long time ago...
...legend has it that a huge Mozu
appeared, attacking the villagers...
...and making them what
is called a hayanie.
Hayanie?
When a Mozu catches insects and frogs...
...and has the trait of impaling
them on tree branches.
Those are the Mozu's prey.
It's characteristic is to stick them on
sharp objects like barbed wire and twigs.
Ah, there, there.
There's one.
Eh? Auntie, that surprised me!
Dad, don't shock them like that anymore.
I'm sorry... Nice to meet you.
I'm his daughter Misa.
"Wakura's Second Daughter Wakura Misa"
I'm helping Wakura
investigate the Otori legend.
I'm Kosaka.
"Graduate Student Kosaka Sho"
We'll be under your care.
I got caught up in the Otori
legend just now. Excuse me.
Come, let's go.
Yes.
"Jyugoya Village"
This is a nice place, isn't it?
But, scary!
Still, the only access to the
village is across this bridge.
So do your best for a little longer.
Yes!
Hey, Ran!
Sorry!
Why are you wearing these shoes for?
You should have brought some
that were more for walking.
You don't understand, Shinichi.
She’s at an age when the emphasis is
more on appearance than practicality.
Appearance? Who's going to be
looking at you here in the mountains?
See, you totally don't get it.
It's okay. I like this.
If you fall, you'll definitely die.
Hey! Hey there!
Shinichi, stop it! You're the worst!
Stop it, you guys! That's dangerous!
It's slippery here. Be careful.
Because you're a guy, you go first.
Don't push, that's dangerous.
All right, I'll go.
You are too strong despite being women.
"Mozutobi Shrine"
What?!
Wow, great.
What are the characteristics
of the village's Otori legend?
It's very similar to the legend recorded on
Forbina ruins from Mayan civilization.
Ever since my school days, I've been
chasing cases across the globe...
...of Otori legend or legendary
monstrous birds.
This is a rare case.
There are these ruins in this village,
so there may be a possibility that...
...they have been transmitted from
ancient Mayan civilization to Japan.
It could be a great discovery.
What is that?
People of the village call it, "God's Perch."
"Mozutobi Shrine God's Perch"
This was the place where sacrifices were made to Lord Otori.
Sacrifices?
Yes.
One would be chosen as a
hayanie and be sacrificed here.
It's said that Lord Otori's wrath would be quelled…
...and that famine and catastrophe
would hopefully not occur.
They can be found anywhere around the village.
Good afternoon.
Ah, good afternoon.
Ah, you have guests?
Yes.
It's great to have such fine weather.
What business do you have at the shrine, Mr. Policeman?
Yes.
I was pressed into helping with
the preparations for the festival.
Uncle, is there a festival?
3 days from now.
What kind of festival is it?
Ah, here at the Mozutobi Shrine,
there's to be a festival to Lord Otori.
In order to calm Lord Otori's turbulent soul...
They'll be dressed as birds and
chant prayers while dancing.
But, for this year only,
this one will be special.
Right, Mr. Policeman?
Ah, that's right. years
A bronze mirror, which is a national
treasure that can only be viewed ...
...once every 300 years will be
here at the inner shrine.
The festival 3 days from now only
comes once every 300 years.
Are you serious?!
Once every 300 years?
We're super lucky, aren't we?
We get to see a hidden mirror
(hikyo) in an unexplored area. (hikyo)
Eh?
Hikyo(coward)?
It means "secret mirror."
Don't make me explain my puns.
Sorry.
But, it really is a secret mirror.
Legend has it that
mysterious things occur...
...when the bronze mirror
resonates with the God's Perch.
What mysterious things?
Ah, from reading the ancient literature...
It’s something like a total solar eclipse.
A total solar eclipse?
But, I'm sure the next cycle
in Japan won't be until 2035.
Ridiculous, isn't it?
But, believers have their dreams.
Most of the people in the village
seem to get a little nervous,...
...thinking of whether or
not they’ll be be cursed...
Since you have come,
please stay here for the festival.
Didn't you listen to what I just told you?
Dad!
Dad, are you okay?
"Wakura's Eldest Son Wakura Yoichi"
Say, what caused this to happen?
"Wakura's Eldest Daughter Wakura Kotomi"
It's unbelievable.
"Wakura's Second Son Wakura Ryoji"
While all of us were walking around
and chatting, then we heard a bird cry.
And suddenly, Kosaka...
It's true! We then realized that
Kosaka had been stuck up there!
It's regrettable that I'm still safe.
What are you saying?
Dad!
Dad.
What's the matter? Does it hurt?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Wakura.
That truly is regrettable.
Brother Ryoji!
Kudo!
Kudo, isn't it?
This person is Megure Juzo.
He's Ran's father's former boss.
He's called the 'Demon
Inspector of the MPD'...
...but in reality, he's also a devoted husband.
What are you doing at a place like this for?
I was invited by Sonoko to come
to a villa here in this village.
Inspector Megure, what are you doing here?
Well, I came to attend a training at this
prefectural police and they said that...
...a murder had taken place, so I came
to help out in the investigation.
It’s Lord Otori's curse!
He’s finally attacking people,
making them hayanie...
It's the legendary Otori becoming real!
In this once-every-300 years festival...
because of the Wakura family's
investigation and excavation of the ruins...
...and selfish behavior,
Lord Otori has been angered!
It's as the storyteller says!
That's right, it's the curse!
The curse! The curse!
Who's the old lady?
She seems to be called "the storyteller."
She must be the one who
manages the shrine here.
Ah... This investigation will be difficult.
Eh...
In order to investigate the corpse,
he will be taken down to the village.
Because we'll be listening to the
circumstances of each of you in turn...
...none of you may leave the village.
And, since the crime
scene must be preserved...
...please refrain from entering the shrine.
Yes!
You are? Let's see...
Ah! Patrolman Haji at your service!
I’m counting on you.
Yes sir!
People can't die from a legend.
This is...a murder case.
This impossible murder mystery...
I will solve it!
"Wakura Family Villa"
Well, well, well... sorry for being late.
This voice is...
Oh, Bret Nelli, where is your house?
Everybody, are you having fun?
Dad...
Why is he here?
Oh, oh?
The conversation doesn't seem
to be as lively as I had imagined.
As I thought, you can't fill in the void
with the detective boy himself.
When it comes to solving mysteries and
socializing, he still has a long way to go!
That man has bad timing.
I see...
This is a murder case.
Most regrettable.
If this detective, Mori Kogoro,
had came just a little earlier...
I would have caught the
criminal just like that.
What are you saying?
If the criminal was stupid enough
to be caught by you...
...Shinichi would have
caught him ages ago.
The detective boy is my pupil.
I taught him everything.
Ah, itchy, itchy!
Here you are.
Thank you.
At any rate, your father seems
to be a huge bird lover.
Birds, here, there and everywhere.
My father is serious about
investigating the Otori legend.
It's amazing how passionate he is…
...to the extent of buying up
all the land in the village.
Excuse me.
When you look closely...he’s hot.
Sonoko, it’s wrong at a time like this.
Now that I, the great detective
Mori Kogoro have come...
...this case is as good as solved.
Please tell your father to be at ease.
Ah, itchy!
If I could have an aperitif, my head
would become increasingly clearer.
Ah, so itchy!
Oh, delicious!
As way of saying thanks…
I, the great detective Mori Kogoro,
will settle this incident perfectly.
Truth is, I have already...
...figured out the criminal.
Who is the criminal?
The criminal is...
The criminal is?
A human!
Everyone...the Otori legend
is just superstition.
In this 21st century, for educated
adults to be misled by a superstition...
...is absolutely disgraceful.
Eh?
Dad, that's all?
Yeah.
Don't you have a concrete
idea about who the suspect is?
Nope!
Excuse me a minute.
The Otori legend, huh?
Aren't such things told to protect
treasure from looters, in many cases?
You’re saying that...there's real
treasure buried in this village?
It's just like looking for the
Tokugawa buried treasure, isn't it?
The Tokugawa buried treasure!
A man's romance!
What man's romance?
The Tokugawa buried treasure, huh?
How should I declare
it on my tax returns?
There is also a romantic
legend in this village.
Eh? What is it? Please tell us.
That lovers who exchange kisses
beneath the God's Perch...
...will never be parted and be married for life.
Kiss...
It's a legend only girls would believe in.
Ran, wants to give it a test!
I won't do that!
Something called Otori that has attacked
village people and made them its hayanie.
And a legend of a kiss in this village.
That's a great mismatch here.
I found this up at the scene just now.
These carvings. I wonder
if they're characters?
They're similar to the characters
used at the Fobina ruins.
If I'm certain, this means "curse."
"Curse"?
Would you know what this fragment is?
Dad?
Dad?!
Wakura?! Wakura! Are you okay?
What is this?
What's going on?
What's happening?
What is this?
Shinichi!
Dad! Are you alright?
Wakura! Wakura!
Uncle, are you okay?
Dad, hang in there.
Damn!
How did it go?
This just struck so suddenly.
What on earth happened?!
Oh? Where's Wakura?
Why are you getting so
worked up over a blackout?
Well, it wasn't about that!
A bird-man suddenly came and...
Yoichi.
Your father had a spasm and Ryoji and the others attended him back to his room.
My father?
His room...?
Didn't you call an ambulance?
-Well that's...
-An ambulance would be overkill.
Having him examined by some
country hospital would be pointless.
If his condition's still bad in the morning...
...we'll take him to Tokyo
to be examined there.
Yeah.
Will he really be okay like that?
He wants to die in the village of the
legendary Otori that he loves so much.
-Isn't that what he wants?
-Sis!
I'm just joking.
Yoichi.
Just where did you go?
Where?
I went to get my cigarettes
from a room.
This.
We place a murder curse
upon the Wakura family...
...who defiles our sacred land.
"Curse"
"Murder"
The criminal most likely left this
fragment at the crime scene on purpose...
...in order to scare Wakura
when he saw this word, "curse".
And clearly, a portion of an entire passage.
If my deduction is correct...
...when the fragments are put back together,...
...the criminal's true
motives will appear.
Hey!
"God's Perch Ruins"
Where are you?
Calling me out in the middle
of the night like this.
Is this about the
distribution of the property?
That sound?
The paper used for letter,
has no characteristics about it.
It's mostly made of old newspapers.
We will never find the person who
issued this threatening letter like this.
We have no choice, but to send it
to forensics and let them investigate it.
Hey!
The detective boy standing there,
were you listening?
Ah...
The Wakura chain has
4,000 branches across the country.
10,000 employees.
Well, given only just those, some
incident is bound to occur every day.
If I could solve this case here
and that became well-known...
...I could be employed by them
as a special-adviser detective.
The Special Adviser Detective,
Mori Kogoro is born!
I'll collect consultant fees
one after the other!
Eh?
Is he serious?
That’s fast...
Somehow, I couldn't sleep.
Ah.
Because something like that happened...
will the festival be cancelled?
Maybe.
But, it only comes once every 300 years.
Once every 300 years, huh?
Shinichi, do you think a full solar
eclipse will really happen?
A full eclipse would be impossible.
Still, I am a little interested in
what might happen.
Hmm...Is being a little
interested all there is?
Eh?
Look, um, well...there's that
romantic story to it, right?
What was that?
Nothing!
What is it?
What are you so angry about?
The lovers who exchange kisses
beneath the God's Perch...
...will never be parted
and be married for life.
Kiss...
Ryoji!
Anyhow, we need to let
Captain Megure know.
It's no good. Like I thought,
cell phones aren’t connected here.
-I’ll go inform him.
-Please do.
Another one.
Like I thought the criminal is leaving
one of these at each murder scene.
Judging from the situation...
...he couldn't have been killed
by being impaled.
So how did the criminal
get Ryoji up there?...
And what is that sound...?
Shinichi.
The phones aren't working.
Dad and the others are
investigating the cause right now.
What was that?
-Don't tell me...
-Wait, Shinichi!
Ran!
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
-No way.
-We were too late.
Shinichi?
The bridge didn't fall on its own.
The criminal cut it down.
How did you know this would happen?
When you told me
the phones weren't working...
...I realized that the criminal was
trying to trap us here to this village.
Until all of his serial killings are over.
All?
You mean it will continue?
Yeah.
Until the pieces are assembled.
-Brother Ryoji! Brother!
-What?
Then we can't leave this village?
No!
The radios at the police station
are also broken...
...and the phones can't be used, either.
The radios, too?
This is Lord Otori's curse.
Lord Otori has gotten angry!
Now, hurry and leave this village!
That's right! Get out right now!
Don't make Lord Otori any angrier!
-Get out!
-Please calm down a little.
Because we'll figure out how
to repair the bridge and phones.
Please return to your homes for now.
For now, please stay
in groups just in case...
...and don't venture out alone.
Please.
The suspension bridge to the other side
from the village has collapsed?
Yeah.
That means the criminal let the
suspension bridge from the village fall.
-In other words...
-Yes.
The criminal is still in the village.
Who will be next?
Who will it be?
It's just like the threatening letter.
Most likely the next one will be...
Me or brother Yoichi...
Or maybe you, Misa.
We finished dinner at 9 pm.
At that time, Ryoji was still here in the villa.
Everyone saw that.
Ran and I went out for a walk
and found his corpse at 11 pm.
Let's confirm everyone’s alibis for those
2 hours, between 9 - 11 pm.
Alibis, you say...
Do you mean that one of us killed Ryoji?
Yoichi.
If you told us, would that cause
some trouble for you?
Ridiculous!
Until around 10 pm, I was with
Ran and her mother talking.
But after that I went to sleep.
I don't have an alibi.
I was just in my room.
It was the same for brother Yoichi
and Misa, wasn't it?
But there's our father, too.
He has no alibi.
This is...
Shinichi, do you understand
what this means?
If I'm not mistaken, this is "betrayal."
This is "curse."
Is this a man.
Is he running?
What sort of meaning
is there to this picture?
Ah, delicious!
Misa, this was freshly-squeezed,
wasn't it?
I'm a man who can tell the difference.
It's just from a regular carton of milk.
Geez... (mou...)
"Moo"? Was that a pun?
That was a pun, right?
Everyone.
You don't seem to have
much of an appetite.
Ryoji and Kosaka's murderer
hasn't been caught.
The phones aren't working and
the suspension bridge has been felled.
The radios at the
police station are broken.
Well, if those were our only concerns,
this wouldn't be impossible.
But please everyone, don't worry.
The name that resound around
the world, Mori Kogoro, is on your side.
Just where in the world
does it resound?
Does your world have
a radius of 1 meter?
-Stop complaining about everything!
-Ah! It's only 50 cm! I’m sorry...
There's something
I'd like to ask all of you.
Was there anyone who bore
a grudge against Ryoji?
No clue...
He did a lot of things, but...
...I don't think he made any enemies
who'd want to kill him.
But, he was in debt, wasn't he?
-In debt?
-Yes.
Ryoji was managing a restaurant
separate from the Wakura chain...
...but it didn't go well.
I don't know the amount
of his debts, though.
Is that so?
By the way, what sort of work
do you do, Yoichi?
Right now I'm raising funds to start
a business making earnings from stocks.
Raising funds?
Yoichi only wanted pocket money, so
he could make tiny trades over the Internet.
Moreover, just the other day
you secretly went to Dad...
...crying about how you have
suffered a huge loss in FX.
That's better than some dull guy
who has to be financially supported.
I heard your boyfriend's a musician
who hasn't even sold a song.
-What did you say?!
-Stop it, both of you.
Man. Why are you
interrogating one another?!
You've still got a long way to go,
detective boy.
Green. Too young.
I already know who the criminal is.
Who is the criminal?
-The criminal is...
-The criminal is?
The criminal is...
-You, Yoichi.
-Huh? Me?
This rare cigarette is yours, isn't it?
I clearly saw you
smoking one yesterday.
And I discovered this one at the site
where Ryoji was murdered.
This great detective's eagle eye
doesn't miss anything!
Give me a break!
Just because I smoke
doesn't make me the murderer!
Jerk! Do you intend
on denying it! You...
I wonder if it is.
Aren’t you going overboard,
accusing Yoichi of being at the scene...
...just because of a cigarette butt?
Huh?
These butts were carelessly left
in every ashtray in the house.
That means anyone who came into the
house would have been able to take one.
-This doesn't mean anything.
-Ah! Hey, hey!
You idiot!
My important evidence!
I regret listening to him.
Well, but Kosaka and Ryoji's death
would really make Yoichi happy though.
What are you saying?
-That'd be you Kotomi, wouldn't it?!
-Please, stop it you two.
Um... Excuse me as well.
I'll go check on father.
I have a favor to ask.
Could you keep an eye on Kotomi?
All right.
And Sonoko, Yoichi.
-What about you, Shinichi?
-For me...Misa.
-How is he?
-He seems to be sleeping well.
I see.
When the suspension bridge
will be restored?
I want to take him to the hospital
as soon as possible.
Kudo, please.
Hurry and catch the criminal.
Yes.
Misa...May I ask you a question?
Kotomi mentioned this earlier.
That if Kosaka and Ryoji were dead,
Yoichi would be happy.
What did she mean by that?
Misa.
When my father declared...
...he would invest his entire fortune
into investigating the Otori legend.
My older brothers and sister
were opposed to it.
At that time, my father told us...
Kosaka should have been my son.
I have no intention of leaving
any of you my assets.
Kosaka would use it more effectively.
It seems that came as a great shock
to my brothers and sister.
Brother Yoichi definitely
seems to be in debt.
But, that's also why
it would be impossible for him...
...to do anything to either
Kosaka or Brother Ryoji.
Give me a break.
Won't you stop acting and wake up?
I'm sure my sister wouldn't have
any reason to, either.
However...after my father became
obsessed with the Otori legend...
...our family’s relationship
had been strained.
"I will tell you how to claim
all of the inheritance."
"Come to Jyugoya Falls'
God's Perch at 3 o'clock."
Thinking about
what might happen again...
...worries and worries me.
How would it come to this?
Thank you.
The God's Perch is about 6 meters tall.
Both Kosaka and Ryoji weighed
more than 60 kilos each, I think.
How did the criminal impale them
up there at that height?
You infidel!
What are you doing?
Do you want to be the fourth hayanie?
Fourth?
What do you mean by "the fourth"?
Who other than Kosaka and Ryoji
were taken as hayanie?
It's best not to wander around
the holy place without good reason.
Please tell me!
Who was it...and when did
he become a hayanie?!
-Don't know.
-Please tell me!
-I said I don't know, so I don't know!
-Please! Please tell me!
The criminal is still...
He’s definitely still in this village!
This isn't the work of a human.
It's Lord Otori's curse.
The Wakura clan set off Lord Otori's
wrath and made themselves hayanie.
The festival will be soon.
What's more, the full solar eclipse
that only happens once every 300 years.
And Lord Otori will certainly appear!
Shinichi!
-What happened?
-Sorry.
When I took my eyes off her,
Kotomi disappeared.
Over there!
Kotomi, are you okay?
Ah, what...
I was just a little startled.
Thank goodness nothing happened.
Shinichi?! Kotomi!
Shinichi!
Kudo! Kudo!
-Ouch...
-Are you okay?
-Somewhat.
-Thank goodness.
-Kotomi, are you hurt?
-No. I'm really very sorry.
It felt like I flew for a moment...
Flew?
What on earth is going on?
What, what is it?
-Where's Ran?
-She was running off in that direction.
Ran!
Ran! Ah~!
Ouch...
Ran!
Uncle?
Ran! Are you okay, Ran!
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Shinichi...
I'm fine.
Ah... geez.
But, I kicked the criminal's
right hand right off.
Ran...why did you do something
reckless on your own for?
Sorry.
Uncle? Uncles? Uncle?!
Dad, what are you doing here?
Dad!
What is this? Making us worry.
I really don't believe this.
It's wet.
No way.
Oh no, I'm drenched! Why?
It's been sunny all day today.
Don't catch a cold.
Thank you.
-But then you'll get cold, Shinichi.
-Fool, I'll be fine.
Thank goodness I'm not alone.
You’re here with me.
Even so, it's pitiful that we are
stuck here and I can't rescue you.
That's not true.
I'm happy that you came.
But...even if it hadn't been me...
You would have rescued
anyone, wouldn't you?
I...
-Did you see that just now? A tanuki.
-That must be a raccoon.
Raccoon?
-Dad, are you alright?
-You said raccoon just now.
-Uncle?
-Where did it go?
If I can catch that raccoon,
I can substitute it for Pascal.
Are you sleep talking?
What's this 'substitute Pascal' talk?
Raccoons are usually called Rascal.
This one's Pascal!
Anyhow, I was chasing after
this raccoon and I ended up down here...
Get ahold of yourself, Dad!
Pascal...
-What about Pascal?
-The French philosopher and physicist.
Pascal's law is the basis
for fluid dynamics...
Mom!
-Auntie!
-Are you okay?
Hey! Hurry and do
something about this!
Say, what are you doing
down there?
Ran's an adult already...
...so if you bother her
anymore, she'll hate you.
That was a big chance
for you two be alone, right?
It wasn't like that!
Itchy, itchy, itchy!
Pascal! Pascal, where are you?
Pascal!!
Why did you go to
that place all by yourself for?
-I was called.
-You were called?
-By who?
-I don't know.
Next thing I know
it's already in my pocket.
-Do you still have that letter?
-I threw it away!
What was written in the letter?
Sister?
"I will tell you how to claim
all of the inheritance."
What's that?
Was the one targeting the inheritance
not me, but you, Kotomi?
You're wrong!
I wouldn't consider such a thing.
However...whoever called me away
may be the one who killed Ryoji.
-The clue to the criminal...
-What's this 'clue'?
Your target is the inheritance!
Please wait, you two.
Inheritance, inheritance!
Dad's not even dead yet!
I'm sorry...that you had
to see something unsightly.
Man?
Bird.
Curse.
Betrayal.
It just needs one more
piece to complete it.
In other words...one more
incident will definitely occur.
I will definitely stop it.
Do you want to be the fourth hayanie?
Who other than Kosaka and Ryoji
were taken as hayanie?
Ah...Good morning.
Good morning.
Come in.
Did something happen?
There's something I'd like you to tell me.
Huh?
At the God's Perch before all this...
...there was someone else who
was a hayanie, wasn't there?
There was?
Leave!
-Please answer me.
-You’re noisy!
It's when Tokyo people like you
come that bad things happen!
Tokyo people?
By "Tokyo people,"
do you mean Mr.Wakura?
Could it be that Mr.Wakura
had been to this village previously?
I have nothing to tell you.
Takezo.
Listen!
Once that suspension bridge's
repaired, hurry and get out of here!
I'm sorry. I was just a little
interested in something.
The references on the history
of the village are all here.
-Would they be helpful?
-Thank you.
"Jyugoya Village Town Hall"
For records on the deceased...
...I guess that I still have to go
to the Administrative Hall.
Oh?
Misa?
This is...a bronze mirror?
I see.
These were opposing mirrors
connected from back to back.
"[Surname] found at the Fobina ruins"
Man?
Similarities between the
Mayan Civilization's Fobina Ruins...
...and Jyugoya Village Ruins.
Mayan Civilization's Fobina Ruins.
Jyugoya Village’s Monster Bird.
Light of the Sun reaches the pyramid.
The bronze mirror
resonates on God's Perch.
Coming down from Heaven.
Flying down from Heaven.
Sacrifice to God.
Hayanie.
"Fobina Ruins"
Underground sewers?
The God's Perches are landmarks
for underground sewers?!
First...This is where Kosaka died.
And here is Ryoji's.
And here is where Kotomi flew...
Konno Machiko.
"Konno Machiko 1986 deceased"
Ha! Don't come near!
This is a place
where the Wakuras and...
...those associated with them
cannot come near!
Leave!
Are you saying that this person’s death
is somehow related to Mr. Wakura?
Is that so?
Was this person a hayanie before?
Please answer me!
Just how much do you know
about the legend of this village?
That long ago, it's said a giant
Mozu bird made a hayanie out of a person.
The bronze mirror in the shrine
resonates with the God's Perch...
...once every 300 years
to cause a full solar eclipse.
And that lovers who exchange
kisses under the Perch...
...will never leave
one another their entire lives.
I see.
Is that everything about the legend?
Isn't there still something left hidden?
That's everything.
If you know the legend...
...then don't let yourself
be attacked by Lord Otori.
Be quiet.
A person can't die from a legend.
-Please tell me everything you know.
-Annoying!
Just before a murder occurs, the sound
of something creaking is heard.
Just what is that?
It's Lord Otori's angry voice.
You've realized it, haven't you?
-Are you okay?
-Yeah, I'm all better now.
Wakura, you mentioned that you have
been investigating the Otori legend...
...and legends of monster birds
since your schooldays, correct?
And?
Have you been to
Jyugoya Village previously?
What are you getting at?
That bronze mirror...
Could it be that this is the original
bronze mirror from Mozutobi Shrine?
Konno Machiko.
You knew her, didn't you?
You know who
the criminal is, don't you?
Is that so?
As I thought...
I know the trick now.
Like I thought, the criminal...
There's no mistake
that it was that person.
The people of the village are worried that...
...it will be dangerous if
you attend the festival.
That's right!
It's best that you not to come.
Is there a law that
forbids me from coming?
Huh?!
You outsider, acting all great!
Outsider?
I am currently the largest landowner
in this village, you know?
You will become
Lord Otori’s his hayanie...
Whatever anyone else may say,
I will attend the festival.
I understand.
I will protect you on that day.
I will be under your care.
-All of you, go home for today.
-Wait a minute!
You’re causing trouble.
Go home. Let’s go.
This murder case hasn't ended yet.
Because the criminal's primary
goal hasn't been achieved yet.
What is the criminal's goal?
"The Day of the Festival"
Somehow, this performance is strange.
Yeah.
Will we be okay!?
Don't worry.
I’m sure that it’ll go well.
"Inner Sanctuary God's Perch"
The village chief and his companions...
Come forward!
Right now, I am
the owner of this village.
Calm down. Calm down.
Lord Otori, calm down...
Calm down, calm down.
Calm down, Lord Otori.
No!
Wa... Wakura!
Wakura!
Huh? It's not!
Dad!
Indeed...
With impossible crime
like being cursed by Lord Otori...
You can't help but think this couldn't
possibly be the act of a human.
However...
The criminal made use of a certain
power to make Kosaka and Ryoji...
...fly up onto the God's Perch where
they were then impaled and killed.
Just like that.
When pressure is applied to water
or air in an airtight container...
That pressure is transmitted to every
part of the fluid with the same energy.
It is a trick utilizing Pascal's principle.
There is a network of underground
sewers beneath this village.
The criminal used that to commit murder.
First, water from the river is channeled
into a hole and temporarily held there.
When the hole’s trapdoor
is opened remotely...
...the water flows down
the hole all at once.
This creates a huge amount
of air pressure.
This air pressure then
spreads through the sewer...
...springing up this slate.
That creaking sound you hear is...
...the sound of the hole’s
trapdoor being opened.
The first victim was Kosaka.
But at that time, the criminal
was actually targeting Misa.
The criminal, his target being Misa...
...chose the timing when
she was standing on this slate...
...and pushed the remote control.
However, his timing was slightly off
and Kosaka who became the victim.
With that failure, the criminal decided
to summon just his target alone.
"Hey, where are you?"
Ryoji...
In the same way,
his next target, Kotomi but...
...that attempt ended in failure.
That was because there wasn't
enough air pressure.
The previous night, Ran had stumbled
over the slate, causing it to slip.
And the criminal hadn't noticed that.
Lastly, the criminal targeted Wakura.
The moment that darkness fell...
...the criminal pressed the remote switch.
However, that darkness was...
...a false solar eclipse created
by Ran and Sonoko.
The criminal had unknowingly
fallen into my trap.
The criminal...
...is you.
-Patrolman Haji.
-Why...?
Why?
Eh?
What evidence do you have?
This is the evidence.
-Ouch!
-Is your hand okay?
Although you are a right-handed person...
...you blocked with your right
hand when Ran kicked...
...and held the screwdriver
with your left hand, right.
Ah, good morning.
What you were fixing
that time wasn't the radio.
But the remote control.
The reason you were attacking
the Wakura family was…
Konno Machko.
Her death is related to this, correct?
30 years ago...
Machiko fell in love with Wakura...
And was the woman
he promised eternal love to.
He betrayed my mother
and abandoned her.
Mom believed in his oath…
Waited...waited and
kept on waiting for him.
I thought so.
Patrolman Haji...
Machiko was your real mother, wasn't she?
Around her memorial there were
flowers and Policeman Haji's footprints.
At the time of Machiko's death,
Haji would have been 4 or 5 years old.
Even today, you still come
visit her grave.
Even after she died
when you were 4 to 5 years old.
That would be unthinkable unless she
had been anyone but your real mother.
You were really that
boy back then, weren't you?
25 years ago...
Machiko suddenly appeared before me.
Who is this child?
She was with a small child.
A relative's child.
This is the shrine’s heirloom bronze
mirror that you wanted to see.
At the time, my business
was gaining momentum...
...and had been the attention
of the mass media.
I was under the impression Machiko
had come to extort money from me.
Mom didn't turn the bronze mirror over
to you because she wanted your money!
She just...
wanted you to remember...
...the vow of love
you had made to her.
My betrayed mother…
...embracing the other half
of the bronze mirror.
I am really...really sorry.
How terrible.
All of the criminal's crimes were...
...to remind Wakura of
his betrayal of Machiko.
And to take revenge for it.
It was my mistake
has led to all of this.
My mistakes has made me...
Lost Ryoji... also lost Kosaka.
And...I had left Machiko to die.
Having been in love during
the days of your youth...
...isn't reason for you
to blame yourself.
But...it's just that
a woman’s life...
...had been driven mad by it.
Your lover's feelings were
too strong for her to bear.
It...wasn't only
Machiko's life. but...
Also your life which
I had messed up.
Are you...
Could it be that you are
mine and Machiko's...
I have no father.
I will never acknowledge
you as my father!
Patrolman Haji!
I spoke to Wakura
about my reasoning.
Wakura says that...
...he doesn’t want you
to commit any more crimes.
By that he risked himself
to cooperate with me.
What a sad, lonely picture.
Policeman Haji.
To you...this crying woman was
just like your mother, Machiko.
These two bronze mirrors...
...when back to back, express
the full details of the legend.
The bronze mirror Wakura had,
contains the character for "man"...
...as the one who
accomplished a betrayal.
On this bronze mirror, this character
perhaps stands for "woman."
This is the woman’s full account.
What do you mean?
Otori is the incarnation of the
woman who was betrayed by her lover.
That's been handed down
generation to generation.
Long ago...
The young couple had vowed and
kissed under the God's Perch.
But the man abandoned
the woman and ran away.
For the woman...
her passions turned into wings...
...and she became
the huge, ugly Otori...
...to attack the man
who had betrayed her.
The woman is said to have become
the Otori to curse and consume the man.
Was the reason you wouldn't
explain all the details of the legend…
...to protect Patrolman Haji?
I...
Took pity on this child and
raised him with my own hand.
So that's it.
So when you told the Wakura family
members to leave this village…
Was it because you didn't
want Patrolman Haji...
...repeating his crimes
any more, wasn't it?
Mom...
Mom, I'm sorry.
After 25 years, the true
bronze mirror has returned.
Ah...
A full solar eclipse.
It's Machiko!
Machiko has come back
as the birds!
A swarm of birds?
Birds...
Did a swarm of birds
block out the sun?
That's incredibly mysterious.
Captain Megure?
How long have you been here?
We finally repaired
the suspension bridge.
I heard the entire story.
Good work, good work.
Seriously?
He was here...
That was a sad case, wasn't it?
Yeah.
-Say, Ran.
-Huh?
About what you said that time.
That time?
When we had fallen into that hole.
I'm happy that you came.
But...even if it hadn't been me...
You would have rescued
anyone, wouldn't you?
I...
Yeah.
...did it because it was you, Ran.
I told you, it's Pascal!
A raccoon is called Rascal!
I've told you, this one's called Pascal!
Once I deliver him to that owner,
everything will be completely settled!
It is impossible that its owner
would be tricked by this.
The main point is that
it has the same fur coat!
It's totally different!
-Mom! Dad!
-Ran.
Where on earth have you two been?
This absurdity of a man here said
he had to catch a raccoon...
So after searching the mountains
calling out, "Pascal, Pascal"...
In the end what he got was...
...this.
This is what you've been
doing all this time?
The entire time.
The main thing is
they're similar, right?
Ah, so itchy.
Still... Pascal turned out
to be a good tip.
Of course.
I knew that from the start.
That's why I kept on
telling you about Rascal.
-You should be thanking me.
-No, it's supposed to be "Pascal."
Wait! Don't leave me behind!
I thought I would help by
saying Rascal and Pascal.
Ah, he's running away.
Wait!
-! was surprised.
-Sorry.
There's always just one truth!